In this segment, we're gonna study the
security of the ElGamal public key
在本节中 我们将会研究EIGamal公钥加密系统的安全性
encryption system. So let me remind you
that when we first presented the
让我来提醒一下大家 当我们第一次展示Diffie-Hellman协议的时候
Diffie-Hellman protocol, we said that the
security is based on the assumption that
我们说过 其安全性是建立在假定
says that given G, G to the A, G to the B,
it's difficult to compute the
给定G G^A和G^B上的 很难计算出
Diffie-Hellman secret, G to the AB. This
is basically what the attacker has to do.
Diffie-Hellman密钥G^A 然而这是攻击者不得不做的
He sees Alice's contribution. He sees
Bob's contribution and then his goal is to
他看到Alice的贡献 看得Bob的贡献 他的目标是
figure out what the Diffie-Hellman secret
is. And we said that this problem is
计算出Diffie-Hellman密钥 我们说过这个问题是很困难的
difficult. The statement that the problem
is difficult is what's called the
这个问题的论断是困难的
computational Diffie-Hellman assumption.
So, let's take this assumption more
即Diffie-Hellman假设的计算是困难的 所以 让我们从更为精确的角度来看这个假设
precisely. So, as usual we're going to
look at a finite cyclic group of order N,
通常我们看一个N阶有限循环群
so G is some group, in your head you should be
thinking ZP star, but there could
G是一个群 大家应该把它想成ZP*
be other groups, for example, like an ellipctic curve group. And then we say that
但也可能是其他的群 比如椭圆曲线群 我们说
the computational Diffie-Hellman
assumption. I've often used the shorthand
计算Diffie-Hellman假设 我通常会用缩写
CDH for Computational Diffie Hellman.
We'll say this assumption holds in G if
CDH来代表Diffie-Hellman假设计算 我们会说这个假设在G上成立
the following condition holds, namely for
all efficient algorithms. If we choose a
如果下列条件成立 即对所有的有效算法 如果我们选择一个
random generator, and then we choose
random exponents A, B in ZN. Then when
随机生成元 然后我们随机选择ZN中的指数A B
we give the algorithm G, G to the A, and G
to the B, the probability that the
我们给定算法G为G^A G^B
algorithm will produce the Diffie Hellman
secret is negligible. If this is true for
算法将会得出 Diffie Hellman密钥的可能性是非常低的
all efficient algorithms, then we say that
the CDH assumption holds for G. CDH, as I
如果这对所有有效算法都是成立的 那么我们说CHD假设在G上是成立的
said, stands for Computational Diffie
Hellman. As it turns out, this assumption
正如我说过的 CDH代表 Diffie Hellman假设算法 实际上 这个假设
is not ideal for analyzing the security of
the ElGamal system. And instead I'm gonna
对于分析EIGamal系统的安全性并不理想
go ahead and make a slightly stronger
assumption called a hash Diffie-Hellman
因此我将要介绍一个更加有效的假设 叫做哈希 Diffie Hellman假设
assumption. Okay. So what is hash
Diffie-Hellman assumption? Again, we are
好的  Diffie Hellman假设是什么呢
focusing on a particular group G and now
we're also gonna introduce a hash function
让我们来关注一下确定的群G 现在我们引入一个哈希函数H
H that maps pairs of elements in G into
the key space of some symmetric encryption
它把G中的元素映射到某个对称加密系统的密钥空间中
system. And then we say that the hash
Diffie-Hellman a ssumption, or HDH for
那么我们就说哈希Diffie-Hellman假设 或简称HDH
short, holds for this pair, G comma H for
the group in the hash function if the
对于二元组（G,H）成立，G是群 H是哈希函数
following is true. Basically, if I choose
a random generator and then I choose
如果以下条件为真 如果我选择一个随机生成元
random exponents A and B in ZN and then I
also choose a random R and K, then the
然后我随机选择Z_N中的指数对A和B 那么我也随机选一对R和K
following distributions are
computationally indistinguishable. That
那么下面两个分布是完全不可区分的
is, if I give you G, G to the A, G to the
B, and then this hash value, this should
也就是说 如果给你G G^A G^B 那么这个哈希值
look familiar to you. This is the hash
value that's used in the ElGamal system to
这你看起来应该感到熟悉 这就是在ElGamal系统中用来推出对称密钥加密的密钥
derive the symmetric encryption key. What
we're saying is that this distribution is
用的哈希值 我们要说的是这个分布是
indistinguishable from a distribution
where you're also given. G, G to the A, G
不能和另一个分布区分的 在另一个分布中你也被告知G G^B G^A
to the B. But now, instead of giving the
hash, you're given just really random key.
现在你不被告知哈希值而是真的随机数
So what this assumption says is that the
symmetric key that was derived during
所以这个假设说的是对称密钥在ElGamal系统中
encryption in the ElGamal system,
essentially is indistinguishable from a
被推出的 完全是不可区分的
truly random key that is derived
independently from the rest of the
与与其余部分独立被推出真正的随机数
parameters of the system. It's a truly
independent random key, looks basically
这是一个真正的独立随机密钥
the same as the key that we used, to
derive from the G to the A and the G to
看起来和我们用过的密钥基本相同 从G^B G^A
the B. Now I'd like to point out that the
Hash Diffie-Hellman assumption is actually
现在我想要指出 哈希Diffie_Helllman假设是
a stronger assumption than the
Computational Diffie-Hellman assumption.
一个比计算Diffie_Hellman强的假设
The way to see that is using the contra
positive, that is suppose the
证明方法是看其反面情况 即假设
Computational Diffie-Hellman assumption
happens to be easy in the group G. Then I
计算Diffie_Hellman假设在群G上容易解决
claim that in fact the Hash Diffie-Hellman
assumption is also easy in the group G. In
那么我要证明事实上哈希Diffie_Hellman假设在群G上也容易解决
fact, I'll say for G, H and this is true
in fact for all hash functions where the
事实上 我会说对于G和H 这是成立的 事实上 对所有哈希函数
image of the hash function. It contains at
least two elements. In other words all I
若哈希的像至少含有两个元素 换句话说
want to say is that the Hash Diffie-Hellman assumption
and it's easy for all
我想说的是哈希Diffie_hellman假设是容易的
hash functions to go match everything to a
single point. Which is true for almost all
如果所有哈希函数把一切都映射到一个点 这对我们感兴趣的
hash functions of interest to us. So
actually, this is a really simple
几乎所有哈希函数都是成立的 事实上 这个命题
statement to prove. Basically, if the
Computational Diffie-Hellman assumption is easy, what that
很容易证明 基本的 如果计算Diffie_hellman时假设是容易的
says is that, given G to the A and G to the B, I can actually calculate G to the AB
也就是说给定G^A G^B 我能算出G^AB
myself. Cuz I know the hash function H, I
can calculate this complete value here. So
因为我知道哈希函数H 我可以完全的计算这里的值
if you give me a tuple that's
sampled from the left or sampled from the
所以你给我一个取样自左边的元祖 或取样自右边的元祖
right. I can very easily tell where it's
from. If it's sampled from the left, then
我很容易就能告诉你它从哪边来 如果取样自左边
once I've calculated G to the AB myself, I
can just test that the last element in the
那么一但我已经计算了G^AB 我能够测试组中最后一个元素
tuple is, in fact, the hash of G to
the B and G to the AB. If it is, I know
是不是G^B和G^AB 如果是 我就知道
the sample is from the left. If it isn't,
I know the sample is from the right. Okay,
取样自左边 如果不是 我就知道取样自右边
so this gives me pretty high advantage, in
distinguishing these two distributions. So
这给我很大的优势 来区分这两个分布
CDH is easy, it's very easy to see that
these distributions are distinguishable.
所以CDH是容易的 很容易看出这两个分布是可区分的
And this basically says that if the Hash
Diffie-Hellman is in fact hard, then CDH
基本可以说 如果哈希Diffie_Hellman是困难的 那么CDH
must also be hard. Which then we say, that
therefore the Hash Diffie-Hellman is a
也会是困难的 之后我们就可以说 因此哈希DIffie_Hellman 是一个
stronger assumption. There might be group
where CDH is hard, but HDH is not hard.
更强的假设 可能有一些群CDH是困难的但HDH是不困难的
Okay. So we say HDH is a
stronger assumption. If you found this
所以我们说HDH是一个更强的假设 如果你觉得
discussion of weak assumption versus
strong assumption confusing, it's not
这种弱假设 强假设的对比困扰 这不是很重要
really that important, it's fine to ignore
it. The important thing that I want to
忽视掉也没什么关系 比较重要的我要展示的是
show you is in fact that the Hash
Diffie-Hellman assumption is sufficient to
事实上哈希Diffie_hellman假设是足够
prove the semantic security of the ElGamal
system. Before we do that let me quickly
来证明ElGamal系统的语义安全 在证明之前
ask you the following puzzle just to make
sure the Hash Diffie-Hellman assumption is
让我问下以下问题 保证哈希Diffie_hellman假设已经弄清楚了
clear. So imagine our key space is  to the 128. So 128 bit strings and our
想象我们的空间是^128 即128位字符串
hash function will map pairs of group
elements into this 128 byte strings.
我们的哈希函数吧一对群元素映射成128位字符串
Suppose it so happens that we chose a hash
function Such that it always outputs
假设我们选择一个哈希函数满足 其输出
strings that begin with zero. In other
words, of the 128 bit strings the most
以0开始 换句话说输出的128位字符串
significant bit of the output is always
zero. If we chose such a hash function,
最高位总是0 如果我们选了这样一个哈希函数
does the Hash Diffie-Hellman assumption
hold for this pair, G comma H. So the
那么哈希Diffie-Hellman假设对（G,H）还成立吗
answer is no it doesn't hold. And the
reason is because it now very easy to
答案是否定的 原因是因为现在很容易
distinguish the two distributions that we
have here. The distribution on the left
区分我们现有的两个分布 区分左边和右边的分布
an the distribution on the right. And the
way you would distinguish the two is
大家将要用来区分这两者的方法是
basically if I choose a truly random
element in K, in  to the 128,
如果我在K=｛0，1｝^128中随机选择一个元素
then mostly it can very well be zero with
probability one half. However, the tuple
那么最高位为0的概率是一半
that's given to me is chosen from the left
distribution, then the most significant
然而当给我的样本是从左边分布选出的时候 哈希值的最高位
bit of the hash will always be zero and
therefore if I see zero, I'm gonna say the
一定是0 因此如果我看到0 我就可以
distribution is a distribution on the
left. If I see one, I'm gonna say the
区分出来是来自左边分布的 如果我看到1 我就可以说
distribution is a distribution on the
right. That will give me advantage one
是来自右边分布的 这将会给我一半的优势
half in distinguishing these two
distributions. And so as a result, the
来区分这两个分布 因此
Hash Diffie-Hillman assumption is false in
this case. So clearly you could see that,
哈希Diffie-Hellman假设在这种情况下不成立 大家可以清楚的看到
even though CDH might be hard in a certain
group G, if you choose a bad hash
即使CDH在群G上可能是困难的 如果你选择了一个不好的哈希函数
function, then HDH will not hold for the
pair G comma H. Okay. But suppose it so
HDH在（G,H）上也不成立 好的
happens that we choose a group G and a
hash function H for which the Hash Diffie
假设我们轩尼泽了一个群G和一个哈希函数H使得哈希Diffie-Hellman假设成立
Hellman assumption holds. And in fact, if
you choose the hash function to be just
实际上 如果你选择的哈希函数正好是SHA-256
SHA-256, for all we know, the Hash
Diffie Hellman assumption holds in the
正如我们所知道的 哈希Diffie-Hellman假设在群ZP*上成立
group ZP star, and holds in elliptic curve
groups. My goal then is to show you that
在椭圆曲线上也成立 我接下来的目标是给大家展示
ElGamal is semantically secure under
the Hash Diffie-Hellman assumption. So let me
EIGamal在哈希Diffie-Hellman假设下是语义安全的
quickly remind you how theElGamal
system works. While we're gonna choose a
所以让我来快速的提醒大家EIGamal系统是如何工作的 我们选择一个
random generator G, we're gonna choose a
random 'a' in ZN, the public key is
随机生成元G 随机选择ZN中的一个a
gonna be G, and G to the A, the secret key
is simply gonna be A. And now here I wrote
公钥就是（G,G^A） 私钥就是A
shorthand for the ElGamal encryption.
Basically, what to encrypt, what we do is
现在我在这里简写了EIGamal加密 想要加密时 我要做的是
we choose a random B. We hash G as being H
to the B. Remember this H to the B is the
选择一个随机数B 计算（G^B,H^B）的哈希值 记住这个H^B就是
g^ab 这就是Diffie Hellman密钥 我们由哈希函数得到了一个
value G to the AB. This is the Diffie
Hellman secret. The hash function gave us
对称加密密钥k 我们用k对信息进行加密 然后我们输出g^b
a symmetric encryption key K. We encrypt
the message with K, and we output G to the
和对称密文 对于解密来说 我们要计算u的值和Diffie Hellman密钥g^a的值
B and the symmetric cipher text. To
decrypt we have to value U, and the Diffie
要导出一个对称密钥 我吗将密文解密
Hellman secret, G to the A. To derive a
symmetric key, we decrypt the cipher text.
然后我们输出明文m 我们来看一下如何论证
And then we output the plaintext message m. So let's see how to argue that,
关于ElGmail在这个哈希Diffie-Hillman的假设下是语义安全的这一点是相对容易的
in fact, ElGamal is semantically secure under
this Hash Diffie-Hillman assumption is
所以我们必须论证 记得我们之前讲的 在语义安全中
fairly simple. So well we have to argue,
remember we had, in semantic security, we
有两个实验 一个实验是 攻击者拥有信息m0的加密
have these two experiments. One
experiment, the attacker is given the
在另外一个实验中 攻击者拥有m1的加密
encryption of m0. In the other experiment,
the attacker is given the encryption of m1.
我将两个实验写在这里 你们注意到
So I wrote the two experiments here. Here
you notice that the attacker starts by
攻击者从向敌手发送公钥开始 敌手会
sending off the public key to the
adversary. The adversary then chooses two
选择两个长度相同的信息m0和m1 之后 如果他得到信息m0的EleGmal加密
equal length messages m0 and m1. And then
if he gets the ElGamal encryption of M0,
这是另一种对于ElGmal密文的速写的方法 相似的
and a kind of rough shorthand for what
ElGamal ciphertext is, okay? Similarly, in
加密1中 他仅仅得到了m1的加密而不是m0
encryption one, he simply gets the
encryption of M1 instead of M0, and
而且两个实验中所有条件都是相同的
everything else is the same about these
two experiments. Now, because of the Hash
在哈希Diffie-Hillman的假设前提下 我们知道即便攻击者看到了g g^a和g^b
Diffie-Hellman assumption, we know that
even though the attacker got to see G, G
我们知道g^b的哈希函数输出值
to the a and G to the b, we know that the
output of the hash of G to the b, G to the
而且g^ab和一个随机值之间是无法被区分的 所以 如果我们用一个
ab is indistinguishable from random.
Therefore, if we replace the actual hash
真正随机生成的独立于其他东西的密钥k来取代哈希函数
function by a truly generated random key K
that's independent of everything else, by
在哈希Diffie-Hillman的假设前提下 攻击者不能区分这两个游戏
the Hash Diffie-Hellman assumption, the
attacker can't distinguish these two
而且 这对于你们来说是一个简单的练习 来向你们展示如果他能够
games. And again, it's a simple exercise
for you to show that if he could
区分这两个游戏 那么他就将打破哈希Diffie-Hillman假设
distinguish these two games, then he would
break the Hash Diffie-Hellman assumption.
但是对于实验1来说也是一样的 攻击者也不能区分
But then the same is true for experiment
one. The attacker also could not
哈希函数的输出和一个真的用于生成挑战密文的随机密钥
distinguish the output of the hash
function from a truly random key, that was
我们观察这两个实验
used to generate the challenge cipher
text. Okay. So now basically we look at
我们就会发现 在这两个实验中到底发生了什么
these two experiments and we realize that,
wait a minute, what's going on in these
所有的条件基本上都是相同的除了在一个实验中
two experiments? Basically everything is
the same except in one experiment, the
攻击者得到了在对称系统下加密的m0 在另一个实验中
attacker gets the encryption under
a symmetric encryption system of m0. In the
他得到了一个在对称系统下m1的加密
other one, he gets the encryption under a
symmetric encryption system of m1 and the
而且 密钥是选择了一个随机的且与其他东西独立的
key is chosen at random independently over
everything else. So by the fact that the
在对称系统是语义安全的条件下 这两个游戏是无法相互区分的
symmetric encryption system is
semantically secure, these two games are
如果他们是可以区分的 那么攻击者就可以
indistinguishable. If they were
distinguishable, then the attacker could
打破这个对称系统的语义安全性
break the semantic security of this
symmetric encryption system. So now we
现在我们证明了这一串的等价性  而且这就证明了最初的游戏
kinda prove this, you know, this chain of
equivalences. And that proves that the
实际上是无法区分的 是可以计算的但是是无法区分的
original games, in fact, are
indistinguishable, computationally
所以ElGamal系统是语义安全的
indistinguishable. And therefore, the
ElGamal system is semantically secure.
正如我所说的 这是一个很容易的由图所诠释的证明
Okay so it's like I said a very simple
proof by pictures and you can make this
而且你们不用花太多功夫就可以把这个变成一个严谨的证明 但是仅有语义安全还是不够的
into a rigorous proof without too much
work. But semantic security isn't enough,
我们真正想要的是选择密文安全性 问题在于 ElGamal是选择密文安全的吗
what we really want is chosen ciphertext
security, and the question is ElGamal chosen ciphertext
事实是 要证明ElGamal的选择密文安全性
secure? So it turns out to prove the
chosen ciphertext security of ElGamal we
我们需要一个更强的假 哈希Diffie-Hellman或者是可计算的Diffie-Hellman
actually need a stronger assumption, Hash Diffie-Hellman or Computational Diffie-Hellman
实际上不足以证明系统的选择密文安全性 就我们所知
are actually not enough to prove
chosen ciphertext security of the system as far
所以要证明选择密文安全性 我们要引入一种新的
as we know. So to prove chosen-ciphertext
security, I'm going to introduce a new
被称为交互Diffie-Hellman的假设
assumption called Interactive Diffie
Hellman assumption. And actually,
事实上从技术来说我们不想要这种假设
technically we really don't like this
assumption. And we're going to try to get
之后需要避免它 但是现在
rid of this, later on. But for now, we
just want to analyze the security of the
要分析基本ELGamal选择密文攻击的安全性
basic ElGamal system against chosen
ciphertext attack. So to argue that it is
这个假设要说明的就是选择密文的安全性
chosen ciphertext secure, here is what the
assumption says. Basically the challenger
挑战者开启和敌手的较量 产生随机数G
starts, you know, plays a game with the
adversary, he generates a random G,
产生两个指数 然后照常告诉敌手a的G次方和b的G次方
generates two exponents, and then he says
to the adversary as usual, G, G to the a
敌手的目标是计算出Diffie-Helman密钥
and G to the b. Now the adversary's goal
is basically to figure out the
主要是ab的G次方 输出V的值如果V恰好等于AB的G次方
Diffie-Helmman's secrets, mainly g to the
ab. He outputs the value of V and he wins
敌手将赢得胜利
the game if V happens to be equal to G to
the AB. So, so far this looks identical to
至今这看上去和计算型Diffie―Hellman假设一致没什么不同
the Computational Diffie-Hellman assumption,
there's no difference - this is
就是除了交互Diffie―Hellman的计算型Diffie―Hellman假设
the Computational Diffie-Hellman assumption
except in Interactive Diffie-Hellman would
给攻击者更多的力量 正因为攻击者有了更多的力量
give the attacker a little bit more power.
So because the attacker has more power,
很难保证假设的安全性
it's harder to satisfy the assumption,
which is why we say that this assumption
这就是这种假设比计算型Diffie―Hellman强的原因
is stronger than Computational
Diffie-Hellman. Now what is this power to be
怎么给予这种力量 我们被给予查询的能力
given? We are given the ability to make
queries. In particular, he gets to submit
尤其是从组G提取两元素 因此U1 V1从组G中消失
two elements from the group G, so U1, V1
disappear from the group G. And then he's
然后被告知是否A的U1次方等于V1 等于则得到1
told whether U1 to the A is equal to V1,
so he gets one. If you wanted the A equals
如果想A等于V1则得到0 否则将是一种奇怪的查询
to V1 get zero, otherwise it's kind of a
bizarre type of query. What, how does it
是什么使得攻击成为可能性 但结果呢 我们需要能向攻击者答复这些查询
be possibly help the attacker? But it
turns out we need to be able to answer
这样能证明备选密文的安全性
these types of queries to the adversary in
order to be able to prove chosen
事实上能进行一次又一次的查询
ciphertext security. And in fact, he can
do these type of queries again and again
能够提出尽可能多的质疑
and again. So he can issue as many
queries like these as he wants and then the
假设指出没有这些质疑不能计算出Diffie―Hellman密钥
assumption says that despite all these
queries he still can't figure out the
换句话说除了质疑
Diffie-Hellman secret, namely despite
making all these queries, the probability
计算出Diffie―Hellman密钥的可能性非常小
that he outputs the
Diffie-Hellman secret is negligible. Okay.
很清楚了这种假设和计算型Diffie―Hellman相比
So clearly if this assumption holds, that the Computational Diffie-Hellman assumption
由于敌手有了更多的能量
holds, because here, the adversary has more power,
and as a result we say that this assumption
结果这种假设比计算型Diffie―Hellman更强
is stronger that Computational Diffie-Hellman, the thing,
we really don't like about this
我们对这种假设真的不满意的地方在于它的互动性
assumption, is the fact, that, it's
interactive, and that the adversary is allowed to
敌手允许向挑战者查询 正如我所说 要避免之后的互动
make queries to the challenger, and as I
said, we're gonna trying to get rid
但是现在我要告诉你是在互动Diffie―Hellman假设
of this interaction later on. But for now
I'll tell you that under this Interactive
以及对称加密系统提供真实可靠的加密的假设之下
Diffie-Hellman assumption and under the
assumption that the symmetric encryption
是在假设哈希函数是理想哈希函数的情况下
system provides authenticated encryption, and
under the assumption that the hash
我们把它称作随机预言
function is kind of an ideal hash
function, what we call the random oracle,
事实上ElGamal系统被选密文安全系统
then in fact the ElGamal system is chosen ciphertext secure and again this
并且这的R0指出随机预言模型中的事实
RO here denotes the fact that it's in the
random oracle model. Which is not
对于我们的目的来说不是那么重要
important, so much for our purposes. The
main thing to remember that under
重要的是记住这个预言也就是互动假设之下
kind of this weird, interactive
assumption we can actually prove that
我们的确能证明ElGamal是被选密文安全
ElGamal is a chosen ciphertext secure.
And as far as we know this assumption
据说这个假设实际运用于组ZP
actually holds for the group ZP star.
So what we're gonna do next is basically
下一步我们要做的是回答能否避免互动型假设
answer this question of whether we can get
rid of the interactive assumption. Can we
我们能证明安全性严格依赖于CDH吗
prove security strictly based on CDH? And
similarly can we proof security without
相应地我们能不依赖随机预言证明安全性吗
relying on random oracles? Just you know
without having to assume, that the hash
你只知道不是得假设哈希函数是理想得到
function is ideal. Just you know, can we
prove security using a concrete hash
你只知道我们能否用具体的哈希函数证明安全性 这个将在下节简要介绍
function. And we'll do that very briefly
in the next segment.